storycorps.org 2011-12-13

# Privacy Policy | StoryCorps

##  Privacy Policy  

Last updated March 15, 2010 

StoryCorps values your participation in our community, both online and offline, and assure you that your privacy is a priority to us. The StoryCorps website adheres to a strict policy for ensuring your privacy and preserving the integrity of this online medium. 

###  Visiting storycorps.org:  

When you visit our site, our web server (like all other web servers) automatically recognizes your IP address, what browser you are using and certain other information (such as the date and time of your visit and a list of files downloaded or viewed). Our web server does not automatically collect personally identifiable information, such as your name or address. We use the information that is collected automatically by our web server to analyze how traffic flows at storycorps.org, but no one can contact or identify you from this information. 

###  Cookies:  

StoryCorps places a standard "cookie" file on your computer to more accurately count the number of visitors and track activity on our website. A cookie is a string of code that can be placed onto your hard drive to enable a website to recognize your preferences when you using the StoryCorps website, such as your preferred text size and the name you prefer to use when leaving comments on the StoryCorps blog. Users have a choice of allowing the cookie to remember these kinds of preferences or typing them each time they visit the site. A cookie can also remember which pages you have visited on the StoryCorps website. Cookies used by StoryCorps do not store any personal information about you. 

###  Uses for Information Collected:  

StoryCorps collects personally identifiable information from its website only if users choose to provide that information to us. The only purposes for which we use such information are to: fulfill newsletter subscriptions and distribute electronic and hard copy newsletters; list users’ names when posted user submitted via email or in comments to the StoryCorps Blog; process donations; and reserve appointments for recording sessions. 

From time to time, StoryCorps shares donor and supporter names and addresses with carefully selected organizations in order to increase our base of supporters. If you do not want your name shared, please contact our Development Department at 646-723-7020 x22 or [support@storycorps.org](mailto:support@storycorps.org). 

StoryCorps may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or if it believes, in its reasonable discretion, that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process, (b) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the StoryCorps website or (c) protect the personal safety or property of StoryCorps website users, the public or StoryCorps employees or agents. 

If you do not want your personally identifiable information to be collected or used for any of the purposes discussed in this privacy policy, you may "opt out" according to the process described below, or contact our Development Department at 646-723-7020 x22 or [support@storycorps.org](mailto:support@storycorps.org). 

You must be at least eighteen (18) years old in order to subscribe to our newsletter or make a donation or reservation. If you are under thirteen (13) years old, please do not submit any information about yourself to the StoryCorps website, including your name, address or email address. If we discover that we have collected any personally identifiable information from a child under the age of thirteen (13), we will promptly remove that information from our server. Visitors between the ages of thirteen (13) and eighteen (18) must obtain permission from one of their parents or guardians before using any aspect of the website, or submitting any personally identifiable information to the website. 

###  Email Communications:  

StoryCorps regularly sends email newsletters and membership correspondence to our registered visitors with information about StoryCorps programs, services, and organization news. Our newsletter works on an opt-in basis. This means that you will not be subscribed unless you explicitly state that you wish to receive the newsletter. If, at any time, you wish to stop receiving the newsletter, visit the email newsletter sign up page to opt-out. 

###  When You Make an Online Donation or Reservation for an Interview:  

StoryCorps will ask you to provide the information necessary to process and service your donation or reservation, including your name, billing address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number. This information is encrypted for your security and is only seen by authorized members of our staff who process the transaction. 

###  Comments/Discussion Board Participation:  

StoryCorps reserves the right to collect the email addresses of those who post comments, messages to our bulletin board, inquiries and other information volunteered by the user, such as survey information and/or site registrations. The information we collect is to ensure compliance with Discussion Board rules (see our [Terms of Service](http://storycorps.org/terms-of-service) for more information) but is never shared with other organizations. 

###  Security:  

When you contribute to StoryCorps online, the information you provide is encrypted using a Secure Socket Layer Certificate (SSL) and transferred using secure protocol to a third party who maintains a secure database. The SSL Certificate will provide 128-bit-encryption as long as users are running 128-bit enabled browsers. StoryCorps ensures that third parties who handle financial and other private information have aggressive security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that has been collected from you at our site. 

###  Links:  

storycorps.org contains links to a wide variety of websites, including some which may not follow the same privacy policies as StoryCorps. StoryCorps is not responsible for the privacy policies of those other sites or how they treat information about their users. Users who choose to follow links from storycorps.org, should make themselves familiar with target sites’ privacy policies. 

###  Changes to Privacy Policy:  

By using this website, you are agreeing to the terms and conditions of this storycorps.org privacy policy. We may change, edit, remove or add sections of this policy at any time. StoryCorps will never use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice without notifying users. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Web site, attempt to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you have additional questions about how your personal information may be used or if you have questions or comments about our privacy policy, please contact us by using our online Inquiries form. 

###  Terms of Service  

Please also make sure to read storycorps.org’s [Terms of Service](http://storycorps.org/terms-of-service) to understand the additional terms and conditions which apply to your use of our website.
